# PRADEEP BISWAS

# Software Engineer

+918319868762 pradeepbiswas41813@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/pradeep-biswas-003886215/ https://github.com/pradeepxdxd Betul, MP, 460440

### **SUMMARY**

I am a MERN Stack Developer with 1.10 years of hands-on experience in developing and maintaining web applications using Reactis, Nodejs, Expressjs, MongoDB. I have a solid understanding of front-end and back-end development, API integration, and database management. Proficiency in JavaScript, responsive design, and RESTful services is essential. Familiarity with version control tools like Git is preferred.

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript, Reactis, Nextis, Redux Toolkit, Nodeis, Expressis, OAuth2 Mongodb, Rest Api's, GraphQL, Git, Github, Gitlab, HTML, CSS, MUI. Bootstrap

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer

NeoSOFT Technology

Pune Maharashtra India

09/2022 - 06/2024

11/2023 - 06/2024

Pune India

## **Projects** Kizuna (Manufacturing of Pump And Motor)

https://www.indi4.io/kizuna/

Role: - Frontend Developer (Reactis)

This project focuses on automating pump and motor manufacturing using Industry 4.0 technologies to enhance operational efficiency, production flow, and overall output.

- Creating interactive user interfaces and implementing features using React, MUI, Redux Toolkit, React Router Dom, XIsx,
- Optimized React application performance through techniques like code splitting and lazy loading, useMemo and useCallback
- · API Integration: Connecting frontend components with backend services through Rest APIs.
- Collaboration & Version Control:- Working in a team environment, collaborating with designers and other developers. Using version control systems like Git, Gitlab for managing codebase.

## Skuview (Sales Prediction and Restock Inventory)

Pune, India

02/2023 - 10/2023

Role: - Full Stack (Nextjs, Nodejs, Expressjs, Graphql)

This project involves building a Sales Prediction and Inventory Management System using data analytics and machine learning to optimize inventory and streamline operations. The system supports sales forecasting, automated purchase orders, and provides a comprehensive view of supply chain activities.

- Creating interactive user interfaces and implementing features using Next.is, Apollo-Client, Redux Toolkit.
- Backend Development (Node.js & Express): Developing server- side logic, APIs, and integrating with databases using Node.js and Express.js, Apollo-Server and also use MicroService, Docker.
- · API Integration: Connecting frontend components with backend services through GraphQL APIs.
- Collaboration & Version Control:- Working in a team environment, collaborating with designers and other developers. Using version control systems like Git, Github for managing codebase.

Personal Projects Remote **JustChats** 

https://justchats.vercel.app

08/2024 - 09/2024

Repository:- https://github.com/pradeepxdxd/JC-Client.git

Technology: - Reactjs, Nodejs, Expressjs, Mongodb

- Created interactive UI using Reactjs, MUI and managing state using redux toolkit and for api calls axios is used.
- Users can chat with each other for that socket.io is used for client and server also implement OAuth2 for Google Login.
- User can make video-call and share their screen for that I use Zegocloud third-party library.
- Deployment using Render for backend and Vercel for frontend.

# Portfolio

https://pradeepbiswas.vercel.app

Technology:- Reactis, Emailis, react-i18next

Powered by CX7 Enhancy

## **EDUCATION**

B.Tech (Computer Science and Technology)

IES IPS Academy

· CGPA:-7.0

Indore

08/2018 - 05/2022

Sarni, Betul 12th MPBSE

01/2017 - 01/2018 Little Flower Higher Secondary School)

· Physics, Chemistry, Maths

· CGPA:-7.7

Sarni, Betul 10th MPBSE 01/2015 - 01/2016

Little Flower Higher Secondary School)

· CGPA:-7.0

**LANGUAGES** 

Bangali (Advanced) English (Advanced) Hindi (Advanced)

**PASSIONS** 

**Movies Gaming**